

Marcus Krejpowicz

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

+49160 85 75 072

<u> marcus.krejpowicz@gmail.com</u>

marcuskrejpowicz.com

Roßmarktstraße 29, 04177 Leipzig

Languages

German

Native

English

Good

Education

2007 - 2012

Comp. Science, Diploma

TU Dresden

Technical Skills

- Software Architecture
- Frontend / Backend
 Development
- SQL / NoSQL
- Testing and Testmanagement
- Operations
- Job Interviews

Interests

- Traveling
- Football
- Surfing
- Gaming
- Boardgames

Summary

I am a senior software engineer based in Leipzig, Germany. I've been building and tweaking web applications for over 10 years. My experience goes from just implementing things to doing job interviews and managing a team of developers. I love to work in small teams with talented and open minded people.

Experience

2019 - today / ProCarement GmbH

LEAD ENGINEER

Lead a team of 7 developers including frontend, backend and QA engineers. Created and implemented the software architecture for a remote patient monitoring software consisting of a Webportal and a REST API (RoR). Setup CI pipelines for the preview and release infrastructure including E2E tests (Cypress + Cucumber). Integrated a test management tool, established coding guide lines, code review checklists and other rules for the development process

2018 - 2019 / Ulysses GmbH

SENIOR DEVELOPER

Migrated the legacy community platform for sharing export styles and editor themes to a new architecture based on PostgreSQL, Ruby On Rails and Solr. Migrated the company blog to the Ghost Blogging system. Designed and implemented a bunch of integration tools and services

2016 - 2018 / Vizzlo GmbH

SENIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Designed and implemented a ReactJS library for building interactive SVG graphics (including a SVG text editor). Worked on the infographic designer and other tools like an MS Office Add-in. Introduced and implemented Selenium and Mocha tests for the frontend and ReactJS library. Designed and build the homepage

2012 - 2016 / Spreadshirt

SENIOR DEVELOPER

Migrated the T-Shirt Configurator from Flash to HTML with a self developed SPA framework called rappidjs. Designed and implemented a multi country/language single page checkout. Collected first experiences with writing E2E tests based on Selenium. Executed maintenance task on the legacy PHP system.